Howard Gillette Collection on the Italian American Community of Washington, D.C., 1980-1986 MS2072
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Howard Gillette Collection on the Italian American Community of Washington, D.C.
1980-1986
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Gillette, Howard, Jr.,, 1942 -
MS2072
3 Linear Feet
Collection consists of a significant number of photographs collected from the exhibit "Washington's Italian Community 1890-Present" developed and sponsored by the Washington Area Studies Department that was held in November 1984; negatives of all materials collected; obituaries; news articles; research notes; correspondence; clippings; and copies of the exhibit flyer and the article Alan Kraut and Howard Gillette did for the "Journal of American Ethnic History."
Restrictions on Access
Some records may be restricted.
Acquisition Information
Howard Gillette donated this collection.
Historical or Biographical Note
The exhibit "Washington's Italian Community 1890-Present" developed and sponsored by the Washington Area Studies Department, was held in November 1984. Alan Kraut and Howard Gillette wrote an article for the "Journal of American Ethnic History" related to the exhibit.
Collection Scope and Content
This is a collection of materials from the exhibit "Washington's Italian Community 1890-Present" developed and sponsored by the Washington Area Studies Department that was held in November 1984. The collection consists of a significant number of photographs collected from the exhibit, negatives of all materials collected, obituaries, news articles, research notes, correspondence, and other clippings, and copies of the exhibit flyer and the article Alan Kraut and Howard Gillette did for the "Journal of American Ethnic History."
Photographs; Italian Americans; Exhibitions; Washington (D.C.) -- History; Washington (D.C.); George Washington University. Center for Washington Area Studies; George Washington University
- Letter to Howard Gillette regarding possible contacts on Italian-American Research in Washington, 1983 October 23 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Letter from Howard Gillette to Research Assistants regarding the Project, 1983 January 11 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Primary Research Notes, Organizational Notes, 1983 December 01 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- A Short Study of Italian Women in Washington, D.C., Mindy Sue Shapiro, 1984 July 24 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Letter and information from Melissa McLoud. Information is regarding photographs of Italian workmen, 1984 June 03 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- The Evolution of Washington's Italian-American Community First draft Fall, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- The Evolution of Washington's Italian-American Community 1890-1980. Presented at the 17th annual meeting of the American Italian Historical Association, Washington, D.C., 1984 November 10 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Washington's Italian Community 1890-Present, An Exhibit by the Center for Washington Area Studies at G.W.U. pamphlet, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Humanities, Spring 1984, Article by Howard Gillette tracing Washington's Italian Community, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Journal of American Ethnic History Fall 1986. This is an offprint of the Gillette/Kraut article, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Critique of Howard Gillette's early draft by research assistants, no date, undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
- The Evolution of Washington's Italian Community 1890-1980, brochure asking for assistant with research, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Questionnaire regarding presentation and exhibit. This is the sort of thing people fill out when they leave an exhibit, undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Article on Italian in NIAF. Clipping from NIAF newsletter regarding Italian migration to D.C. in 1980s, undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Ethnic composition of Metropolitan Area. The photocopy from the newspaper may have no date, but the data is from 1970 census, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Research notes regarding various professions held by Washington Italians, undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
- List of businesses on 9th St., NW, between H and Eye. Handwritten lists of businesses by types. Photocopy of an alphabetical list of businesses, with last names beginning with A, undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Clipping from The Hill Rag, 01/09/1984, on Litteri's, a deli on Morse Street between 6th Street and Florida Avenue NE. Business opened by Antonio Litteri, who arrived in the U.S. in 1926, lived briefly in New York, and then came to D.C., where he stationed a produce wagon in the market at 16th and K NW. In 1932 he moved to the present shop. He had no children, so his brother-in-law Mariano De Francisci took over, and now De Francisci's sons. Clipping from the Washington Post, 12/12/1972, Betty Medsger, "Area Italians Proud of Accomplishments." Highlights the Catania Bakery 1404 North Capitol Street (we went by it on our way to and from the John Paul II Cultural Center), which the Caruso family opened on Labor Day 1932. It supplies bread for the Villa Rosa fall festival. Also the Italian Groceries Store, 1317 Pennsylvania Avenue, run by Anna Mangialardo and her son Antonio. She was born in the United States, the daughter of a coal miner who went back to Italy with her family as a child and then came back to the United States with her husband, 1972-1984 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Handwritten notes from Polk's Directory for 1910 listing Italian names, addresses and occupations, undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Handwritten notes from Polk's Directory for 1915 listing Italian names, addresses and occupations, undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Material from Italian organizations, specifically: Italian Cultural Society, Fiumedini, Sons of Italy. It includes fifteen photographs, a silver anniversary book, undated (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Material from Italian organizations, specifically: Lido Club, Italian Cultural Society, undated (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Italian obituaries, not sorted, undated (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Material from Holy Rosary. This includes photocopies of material from the Archdiocese of Baltimore and the Center for Migration Studies (repository of Father De Carlo's papers and Holy Rosary's parish papers), and souvenir booklets, undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
- A souvenir book from Holy Rosary, undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Miscellaneous Obituaries, not sorted, undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Abbo [Frank Abbo, owner of Roma Restaurant near uptown Connecticut Avenue, undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Abernathy. Walter S., transportation specialist with Dept. of Commerce, undated (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Addabbo, John J., CPA and saxophonist, undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Agazzi, Arturo, waiter, undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Alongi, Thomas, mechanic, undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Amato, Joseph A., barber, undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Anastasi, Angelina, seamstress, HOLY ROSARY, undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Aninto family, 1940 directory information, undated (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Antonelli, Dominic HOLY ROSARY, undated (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Antonio, Sam, Udine-bom tile setter who set tile at the U.S. capitol, the Naval Observatory, the Library of Congress and several embassies, undated (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Aquilino, Paul A. HOLY ROSARY, undated (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Arcaro, Michelina L, undated (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Arthur, Kenneth Board, undated (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Ayers, Robert R, undated (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Bahen, Joseph B., builder of tomb of unknown soldier, undated (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Balamoti, Michael J., chief of banquets at the Washington Hotel, undated (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Balducci family HOLY ROSARY, undated (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Barazotta. Inside is a card regarding Henry Barazotto of Clement's Pastry Shop, undated (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Barbera,, Joseph, baker, undated (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Baroni, Geno C, undated (Box 3, Folder 20)
- Barranca, Nicola, shoemaker, undated (Box 3, Folder 21)
- Beccanari. Inside is a card on Nina Baccanari, undated (Box 3, Folder 22)
- Bello, Michael, Sr., HOLY ROSARY, undated (Box 3, Folder 23)
- Benninghoven, Roland N., realtor, undated (Box 3, Folder 24)
- Bhussry, Baldev Raj, anatomy professor at Georgetown, undated (Box 3, Folder 25)
- Bianchi. Inside is card on Don and Lydia Bianchi HOLY ROSARY, undated (Box 3, Folder 26)
- Bichicchi, Maria, grocer, undated (Box 3, Folder 27)
- Biondi, Giovanni, tile setter HOLY ROSARY, undated (Box 3, Folder 28)
- Bixel, Charles P., army brigadier general, undated (Box 3, Folder 29)
- Black, Louis Woolfolk, undated (Box 3, Folder 30)
- Bliss, Joseph H, undated (Box 3, Folder 31)
- Boccabella, Reno W., grocer HOLY ROSARY, undated (Box 3, Folder 32)
- Bolen, Elizabeth A, founder of House of Blessing, undated (Box 3, Folder 33)
- Bonanno, Rosaria, widow, undated (Box 3, Folder 34)
- Bonnuccelli, Joseph, chef, HOLY ROSARY, undated (Box 3, Folder 35)
- Bonuso, Joseph Michael, undated (Box 3, Folder 36)
- Boratenski, Florence Grant, undated (Box 3, Folder 37)
- Bottari, Natale V., tailor HOLY ROSARY, undated (Box 3, Folder 38)
- Bovello, Charles J, undated (Box 3, Folder 39)
- Brienza, Orlando, fire fighter HOLY ROSARY, undated (Box 3, Folder 40)
- Bruno, Agatina M., Bruno Brothers Ornamental Ironworks (wife of one of the brothers), undated (Box 3, Folder 41)
- Burkhart, Nadia HOLY ROSARY, undated (Box 3, Folder 42)
- Burgess, Hardy, structural engineer, undated (Box 3, Folder 43)
- Caffi, Horace Orazio, mason HOLY ROSARY, undated (Box 3, Folder 44)
- Caffo, Domenico, shoe repair, undated (Box 3, Folder 45)
- Cairo, Frank A, undated (Box 3, Folder 46)
- Calcara, Frank J., builder HOLY ROSARY, undated (Box 3, Folder 47)
- Caporaletti family HOLY ROSARY, undated (Box 3, Folder 48)
- Carchedi, Rosina, undated (Box 3, Folder 49)
- Cardinale, Vito, tile setter for the Truman white house, undated (Box 3, Folder 50)
- Carlantonio, Alphonso Di, worked for Washington terminal Company, undated (Box 3, Folder 51)
- Carosi, Nicholas Sr., sculmptor and coiftractor HOLY ROSARY, undated (Box 3, Folder 52)
- Caruso, Ugo, interview, undated (Box 3, Folder 53)
- Caruso, Joseph J., florist, undated (Box 3, Folder 54)
- Casassa, Lillian, candy business, undated (Box 3, Folder 55)
- Cascio, Lucia C., HOLY ROSARY, undated (Box 3, Folder 56)
- Catella, Michael, grocer, HOLY ROSARY, undated (Box 3, Folder 57)
- Catucci family HOLY ROSARY, undated (Box 3, Folder 58)
- Ceccarelli, Americo, tile setter who worked on the mosaics at the Catholic Shrine of the Blessed Sacrament, undated (Box 3, Folder 59)
- Cerimele, Costanzo, Deputy U.S. Marshal, undated (Box 3, Folder 60)
- Checchia, Vito. Barber. HOLY ROSARY, undated (Box 3, Folder 61)
- Chicca, Edward A.J, undated (Box 3, Folder 62)
- Chirieleison, Casper J. World War II veteran, undated (Box 3, Folder 63)
- Chite family. Barber and beauty shop owner, undated (Box 3, Folder 64)
- Ciaraldi, Americo S. Defense contract negotiator, undated (Box 3, Folder 65)
- Cicala, Conte Luigi. Tailor. HOLY ROSARY, undated (Box 3, Folder 66)
- Cipriano, Ralph. Life insurance sales man. HOLY ROSARY, undated (Box 3, Folder 67)
- Clime, Donald. Fire fighter, undated (Box 3, Folder 68)
- Colaianni, Joseph. Index card. HOLY ROSARY, undated (Box 3, Folder 69)
- Colanero, Vincenzo. Stonemason. HOLY ROSARY, undated (Box 3, Folder 70)
- Cole, Blanche Mack. Matron in the Order of the Eastern Star, undated (Box 3, Folder 71)
- Colella, Eugene F. Internatl Revenue Service attorney, undated (Box 3, Folder 72)
- Colston, Walker H. Wholesale liquor distribotor, undated (Box 3, Folder 73)
- Comignani family. Plasterer and his widow. HOLY ROSARY, undated (Box 3, Folder 74)
- Condatore, Salvatore Luigi. Grocer. HOLY ROSARY, undated (Box 3, Folder 75)
- Corso, Darwin. Electrical contractor, undated (Box 3, Folder 76)
- Corvelli Henry E. Dry cleaner. Lido Civil Club, undated (Box 3, Folder 77)
- Cotturo, Concetta. Widow of Antonio. HOLY ROSARY, undated (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Curro family. Shoe repair and seamstress. HOLY ROSARY, undated (Box 4, Folder 2)
- D'Addario, Gabriel. Postal worker. HOLY ROSARY, undated (Box 4, Folder 3)
- D'Ambrosio family. Index card, undated (Box 4, Folder 4)
- D'Avella, Giovanni. Owned Di Giovanni Coiffures, undated (Box 4, Folder 5)
- De Carlo, Nicolo. Catholic priest. HOLY ROSARY, undated (Box 4, Folder 6)
- de Cesare, Pompeo. Band master. HOLY ROSARY--not a member, but lived on 9th St., NW, undated (Box 4, Folder 7)
- DeFrancis, Mrs. Thomas J. Beautician and pizza maker, undated (Box 4, Folder 8)
- DelBianco, Wilda Hasty. Government printer, undated (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Del Grosso, Michele A. Shoe repair. HOLY ROSARY, undated (Box 4, Folder 10)
- DeLisio, Jerry. Barber, undated (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Della Franca, Benjamin. Litteri grocery meat department manager. HOLY ROSARY, undated (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Dellenoci, Vito A. Beautician. Silver Spring, undated (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Del Vecchio, Charles. Photographer. HOLY ROSARY, undated (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Demma, Joseph J. Tile setter, airport limousine driver. HOLY ROSARY, undated (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Dercola, Pasquale. D.C. Transit worker, Hillandale Barber Shop owner, undated (Box 4, Folder 16)
- Desio, Delphine. Musician. Philadelphia, undated (Box 4, Folder 17)
- DeSiorgi family. Questionnaire, undated (Box 4, Folder 18)
- Di Bietetto, Isabelle C. Ahern. Wife of detective on safe squad, undated (Box 4, Folder 19)
- Di Carlo, Innocenzo. Washington Terminal Company worker. HOLY ROSARY, undated (Box 4, Folder 20)
- DiLorenzo, Mr. Giacomo. Widow. HOLY ROSARY, undated (Box 4, Folder 21)
- Di Meglio, Julian. President of construction company. Lido Civic Club, undated (Box 4, Folder 22)
- DiRienzo, Antonio. Barber. HOLY ROSARY, undated (Box 4, Folder 23)
- Di Rienzo, Frank. Restaurateur, HOLY ROSARY, undated (Box 4, Folder 24)
- Di Rienzo, Joseph. Restaurateur, HOLY ROSARY, undated (Box 4, Folder 25)
- Di Rienzo, Nunziata. Restaurateur, HOLY ROSARY, undated (Box 4, Folder 26)
- Ditoto, Joseph. Plumber and grocery store owner. HOLY ROSARY, undated (Box 4, Folder 27)
- Dixon, Keith D, undated (Box 4, Folder 28)
- Donanzan, Caesar. Catholic priest. HOLY ROSARY, undated (Box 4, Folder 29)
- D'Onofrio, Maria Mezzacappa. HOLY ROSARY, undated (Box 4, Folder 30)
- Economos, Moses. Owner of the Light House and Fish Boat takeout stores, undated (Box 4, Folder 31)
- Eliades, George. Restaurant owner, undated (Box 4, Folder 32)
- Ellis, Oscar F. Buyer for R. Harris Jewehy, undated (Box 4, Folder 33)
- Emanuele, Vincent. Tailor. Saint Gabriel's, undated (Box 4, Folder 34)
- Enfante, William P. Feature obituary on a man who resembled Lyndon Baines Johnson, undated (Box 4, Folder 35)
- Esposito, Vincent J. West Point general, undated (Box 4, Folder 36)
- Fabrizio, Vito. Tailor, undated (Box 4, Folder 37)
- Fato, John B. barber. Saint Jude's, undated (Box 4, Folder 38)
- Federico family. Obituary for Frederick, a baker and World War II veteran. Patent Office Society article on P.J. (Pat) Federico, author and public servant, undated (Box 4, Folder 39)
- Fianzoni, Joseph D. Index card, undated (Box 4, Folder 40)
- Figliozzi, Nunzia. Widow. HOLY ROSARY, undated (Box 4, Folder 41)
- Fioramonti, Ciro. Widow of shoe maker. HOLY ROSARY, undated (Box 4, Folder 42)
- Fleri, Joseph. Shoemaker. Saint Teresa's, undated (Box 4, Folder 43)
- Floreno, Diego (Di). Owner of Caffe Italiano. HOLY ROSARY, undated (Box 4, Folder 44)
- Fontana family. Obiutary on Andrew E., owner of Fontana Bowlarama. Obituary on Elvira, widow of tailor, undated (Box 4, Folder 45)
- Forami, Leo P. Mayor of Capitol Heights, undated (Box 4, Folder 46)
- Fox, Leon A. Brigadier general, undated (Box 4, Folder 47)
- Fralleone, Nan E. Photocopy of prayer card, undated (Box 4, Folder 48)
- Froio, Giuseppe. Shoe maker. Saint John the Baptist. Silver Spring, undated (Box 4, Folder 49)
- Facchina family. Christopher was captured by fascists during World War II, and survived to become a contractor for ceramic tile, marble and terrazzo. John Joseph was a contractor, undated (Box 4, Folder 50)
- Gallerizzo, Pietro. Potomac Electric Power Company streetlight division. HOLY ROSARY, undated (Box 4, Folder 51)
- Galotta, Henry. D.C. fire chief. Lido Civic Club, undated (Box 4, Folder 52)
- Gates, Pearl W. Physician's widow, undated (Box 4, Folder 53)
- Gatti, David M. Index card, undated (Box 4, Folder 54)
- Gatto, Joseph. Index card, undated (Box 4, Folder 55)
- Gearhardt, Harrison A. General, chief of the office of legislative liaison, undated (Box 4, Folder 56)
- Gervasio, Filippo. Index card, undated (Box 4, Folder 57)
- Gesuero, Pasquale V. Deputy U.S. marshal, undated (Box 4, Folder 58)
- Ghilardi, Ersillo. Index card, undated (Box 4, Folder 59)
- Ghiseli, Angelo. Index card, undated (Box 4, Folder 60)
- Gianetti family. Ornamental plaster., undated (Box 4, Folder 61)
- Gagliardi [note alphabetical order] family. Lamp lighters, undated (Box 4, Folder 62)
- Giannini, John. Restauranteur, undated (Box 4, Folder 63)
- Giannetti, Ettori (Ed). Lawyer and builder, undated (Box 4, Folder 64)
- Giove, Gaetano. Owned Trinidad rambler, undated (Box 4, Folder 65)
- Giuffreda, Antonio. Stonemason. HOLY ROSARY, undated (Box 4, Folder 66)
- Giuliani family. Elisa (Mrs. Giuseppe) operated a grocery story and then State Liquors. Orlando A. Giuliani owned Jimmy's Cafe. Charles and his uncle Joseph worked for American Mosaic and opened Standard Art Marple and Tile Company. Also included is a photocopy of an obituary of Vincent S. Pisciotta who worked two jobs. payroll liaison supervisor of the Bureau of Labor Statistics and sales man specializing in large appliances for Hecht Company., undated (Box 4, Folder 67)
- Giusti, Idamo. Chef. HOLY ROSARY, undated (Box 4, Folder 68)
- Glezos, Emmanuel. Worked for James Economides Produce, undated (Box 4, Folder 69)
- Gnerro, Antonio. Hotel worker. HOLY ROSARY, undated (Box 4, Folder 70)
- Grant, Robert F. applied Physics Laboratory of Johns Hopkins University, undated (Box 4, Folder 71)
- Grasso, Salvatore. HOLY ROSARY, undated (Box 4, Folder 72)
- Graves. Incomplete photocopy, enough to show that Graves was a sergeant in the army and that he was a boxing champion, undated (Box 4, Folder 73)
- Green, Julia Shonk. Soprano, undated (Box 4, Folder 74)
- Grimaldi family. Saverio J. Senior worked for the Naval Ordnance Laboratory planning and progress division. Paul was a tailor. Fiumedinisi Club, undated (Box 4, Folder 75)
- Grinnell, Olga H. legislative aid, undated (Box 4, Folder 76)
- Guglielmino, Lucia V. Seamstress. HOLY ROSARY, undated (Box 4, Folder 77)
- Guttadore, Salvatore P. Contractor, undated (Box 4, Folder 78)
- Hamm, Joseph F. Cartographer, undated (Box 4, Folder 79)
- Hiehle, Wilber W. Army surgeon, undated (Box 4, Folder 80)
- Hunt, Horace L. Junior. Owned Chula Vista Nursing Home, undated (Box 4, Folder 81)
- Iacangelo, Violet. Southern Railway System employee. HOLY ROSARY, undated (Box 4, Folder 82)
- Frank, Ignatius N. Prayer card, undated (Box 4, Folder 83)
- Ihrie, John R. Fire fighter, undated (Box 4, Folder 84)
- Innocenti family. John owned a shoe repair shop. Anna was his widow, undated (Box 4, Folder 85)
- Izzo, Anthony. Owned bricklaying company. HOLY ROSARY, undated (Box 4, Folder 86)
- Jenkins. Partial photocopy of obituary, enough to determine the deceased was a man who was successively a driver for Capital Transit, a driver for the Gray Line, and an investigator for the National Detective Agency, undated (Box 4, Folder 87)
- Jolliffe, James. Internal Revenue Service employee, undated (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Kackle. Partial photocopy of obituary; the deceased died in a hold-up, undated (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Kalavritinos, Mr. Christofiles. Partial obituary of the widow of a restauranteur, undated (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Kane, Wilbur F. Partial obituary; the deceased worked for the Interior Department, undated (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Karl, Edmund O. Junior. Car repair business manager, undated (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Kathas, John. Restauranteur, undated (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Krauss, Morris C. (Bill). Duckpin bowling champion, undated (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Lackman family. Index card., undated (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Lambis, Julia (Judy). Victim of Cooley's anemia, undated (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Larson, Joseph R. Victim of carbon monoxide poisoning, undated (Box 5, Folder 10)
- Latona, Salvatore J. Pharmacist, undated (Box 5, Folder 11)
- Layton, Olin W. Partial photocopy of obituary, undated (Box 5, Folder 12)
- Leemans, Alphonse (Tuffy). Football player, undated (Box 5, Folder 13)
- Lemanski, Raymond C. Social studies teacher, undated (Box 5, Folder 14)
- Leonardi, Marco. Railroad worker. HOLY ROSARY, undated (Box 5, Folder 15)
- Leone, Marietta G. Wife of Anthony, a meat cutter for Safeway. HOLY ROSARY, undated (Box 5, Folder 16)
- Lewis. Partial photocopy of obituary; deceased was a woman who used to work for the Army. She organized the Prisoner of War Information Bureau during World War II, undated (Box 5, Folder 17)
- Lindsay, Karen R. Victim of automobile accident, undated (Box 5, Folder 18)
- Litteri. Grocers, undated (Box 5, Folder 19)
- Longo family. Alfio was a shoemaker. Grace was his widow, undated (Box 5, Folder 20)
- Lozupone family. Jean F. was a volunteer with many Italian and Catholic agencies. Vitgo, Thomas, and Constantine were plasterers, undated (Box 5, Folder 21)
- Lunghi, Edmondo. Tailor. Saint Mark's, undated (Box 5, Folder 22)
- Luzzatto, Bruno B.A. NATO advisor. Member of the United Nations Relief and Rehabilitatin Mission to Italy in 1948, undated (Box 5, Folder 23)
- Maciulla, Joseph Di Lorenzo. Ran delicatessen. HOLY ROSARY, undated (Box 5, Folder 24)
- Maggi, Pasquale J. Central Intelligence Agency worker. Saint James, undated (Box 5, Folder 25)
- Magista, Biagio. Stone Mason., undated (Box 5, Folder 26)
- Magri, Carmela. Seamstress. HOLY ROSARY, undated (Box 5, Folder 27)
- Malia, Antonio J. Restaurateur. HOLY ROSARY, undated (Box 5, Folder 28)
- Mallas, Bessie. Widow of railroad worker, undated (Box 5, Folder 29)
- Mancuso family. Nelli Spano Mancuso was a secretary for the U.S. Shipping Board and a volunteer with Baptist activities. There are also index cards on Mancuso's Food., undated (Box 5, Folder 30)
- Manganaro family. Raphael was a physician and Peter a Catholic priest. HOLY ROSARY, undated (Box 5, Folder 31)
- Mangialardo family. Grocers, undated (Box 5, Folder 32)
- Mantuso family. Fruit vendors. HOLY ROSARY, undated (Box 5, Folder 33)
- Marchetti, Philip. Worked in Bureau of Standards optical shop. HOLY ROSARY, undated (Box 5, Folder 34)
- Marchi, Joseph I. Mosaic workers, undated (Box 5, Folder 35)
- Mariani T.G. Dancing academy owner, undated (Box 5, Folder 36)
- Marino, Lucia Rosata. Widow of liquor dealer. HOLY ROSARY, undated (Box 5, Folder 37)
- Marinori, Antonio. Index card, undated (Box 5, Folder 38)
- Marmnucci, Francesco. Farmer. HOLY ROSARY, undated (Box 5, Folder 39)
- Marletta, Angelo. Restaurateur. Lido Club, undated (Box 5, Folder 40)
- Marrocco, Pasquale Luigi. Restaurateur, undated (Box 5, Folder 41)
- Marsanopoli, Anthony. Barber, undated (Box 5, Folder 42)
- Martinelli, Mildred Rosa. Volunteer for Catholic activities, especially her parish of Saint James, Falls Church, undated (Box 5, Folder 43)
- Mascetti, Louis. Shoe shop. Saint John the Baptist, undated (Box 5, Folder 44)
- Massino family. HOLY ROSARY, undated (Box 5, Folder 45)
- Mastradone, John P. Housing and Urban Development, undated (Box 5, Folder 46)
- Mastrangelo, Ellen B. Election judge. Methodist, undated (Box 5, Folder 47)
- Mastromarmno family. HOLY ROSARY, undated (Box 5, Folder 48)
- Mavrikes family. Victims of automobilie accident, undated (Box 5, Folder 49)
- McAuliffe, Anthony C. General at the Battle of the Bulge, undated (Box 5, Folder 50)
- Mehlfelt, J. Rowe. Industrial engineer, undated (Box 5, Folder 51)
- Messina, Angelo. International Telephone and Telegraph Company messenger, undated (Box 5, Folder 52)